



□ +380935374841 | Main hi@shal.dev | Ashal.dev | In ashanaakh

"With hard work and effort, you can achieve anything."

## **Summary**

Currently Lead Golang Engineer at J:Mind:Systems. More than 3 years of experience specializing in the backend, concurrency and microservices. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools. As for sport I like swimming and cycling. Travelling is my passion, I like to discover new places and inspire by amazing views.

# Skill Highlights.

Programming Languages Golang, Ruby, Python, C++

DevOps Docker, Kubernetes, Traefik Cloud Terraform, AWS, GCP

Database MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, Mongo Languages English, Russian, Ukrainian

### **Education**

#### Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv

BACHELOR IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

• My GPA is 4.39/5

Taras Shevchenko National University of Kyiv

MASTER IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Kyiv, Ukraine

2015 - 2019

Kyiv, Ukraine

2019 - PRESENT

## **Experience**

**OpenCars** Kyiv, Ukraine

GOLANG ENGINEER

• Software designing and implementation

- · Telegram bot management
- Specifications development
- Deployment automation

#### J:Mind:Systems

LEAD GOLANG ENGINEER

- Designing of project architecture
- OpenAPI/AsyncAPI specification for APIs
- · Interviewing new candidates
- · Code review
- Designing database schema
- · Documentation of the project using UML
- · Work with different cloud providers
- · Video processing/streaming
- Work with blockchain

#### J:Mind:Systems

GOLANG ENGINEER

- Designing and implementation of different APIs
- OpenAPI specification for APIs
- Automation of KYC verification
- · Work with AWS services: S3, Rekognition, Aurora
- Work with Tesseract OCR Engine
- · Designing database schema
- Documentation for the software
- Interviewing new candidates

Feb. 2020 - PRESENT

Kyiv, Ukraine

Oct. 2019 - PRESENT

Kyiv, Ukraine Oct. 2019 - Feb. 2020

ALI SHANAAKH

**OpenWare** Kyiv, Ukraine Dec. 2018 - Oct. 2019

GOLANG ENGINEER

• Writing idiomatic and resillient Go code

- Software architecture construction and designing
- Specifications and requirements development
- · Code review
- High loaded software development
- · Closely coached and mentored new project member

### MyTimeTable

Jun. 2019 - Sep. 2019

- Inftastructure as code development
- Implementation of docker images • Implementation of CI/CD pipelines
- Managing project on DigitalOcean

### **Helios Technologies**

**DEVOPS & BACKEND ENGINEER** 

- Ruby on Rails Development
- Golang development
- Assembling components using Docker
- DevOps tools development
- Managing projects on Google Cloud Platform
- Build plugins for CI/CD tools
- Build advanced deployments using Kubernetes
- Development of complicated terraform modules
- Design & Implement in-cluster high-speed workers

#### **Palestine Nights**

CO-FOUNDER & FULL STACK ENGINEER

- Software designing and implementation
- · Specifications development
- Deployment automation
- Development of APIs
- DigitalOcean deployment automation

## Kyiv, Ukraine

Kyiv, Ukraine

Jun. 2017 - Dec. 2018

Al Muharraq, Bahrain Sep. 2018 - Dec. 2018

# **Program Committees**

2018 Team Member, Google Hash Code Hackathon Kyiv, Ukraine **Opensource Initiative Winner**, Websummit 2018 Lisbon, Portugal 2019 Visitor, iForum Kyiv, Ukraine 2019 Visitor, IT Weekends Kyiv, Ukraine

ALI SHANAAKH